<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rishabh Chhabra</title>
    <description>Scribbles, anecdotes and geeky blog posts of Rishabh Chhabra.</description>
    <link>https://rishabhc.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://rishabhc.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>The Bechdel Test</title>
        <description>&lt;h6 id=&quot;i-wrote-this-as-an-article-for-geek-gazette&amp;#39;s-spring-2015-edition.&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;I wrote this as an article for &lt;a href=&quot;http://gg.ieeeiitr.com/&quot;&gt;Geek Gazette&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; Spring 2015 edition.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the gender inequality becomes more and more significant in today’s world and Emma Watson promotes #HeForShe further, one must wonder does sexism prevail in the geekdom? If your answer is not an obvious yes to this question prepared to be cut into infinitesimally small pieces by feminists. Once you recover from being chopped into substances smaller than your enthusiasm for studying, you might ask, how do we know sexism exists? Is there an indicator of the same? Be prepared for enlightenment because there is indeed one and it’s called the Bechdel Test.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Bechdel Test is primarily applied to movies and is an indicator of gender portrayal in media. To pass the test a movie needs to satisfy three conditions. First, the movie should have at least two women characters. Second, these women should talk to each other and third, they should talk about something other than a man. Seems simple enough, doesn’t it? Two women talking to each and the point of discussion not being men throughout the whole movie. Think about the most recent movie you saw and whether it satisfies this or not or well, leave it, and think about the last movie you watched which actually passes the Bechdel Test. Hard to find one? Don’t be surprised because a vast amount of geeky media actually fails this test.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To add to your apparent shock, let us list out a few famous movies which apparently fail this test too. Lord of the Rings, with a cast whose sheer number exceeds that of a small country, doesn’t succeed to pass the test. They have strong female characters like Arwen, Eowyn, and Galadriel but they never meet each other and hence the movie is unable to meet the second condition. Another movie in which the possessors of the XX chromosome do not talk to one another is The Social Network. There’s even a scene of doing the nasty in the bathroom but god forbid that the women talk to each other! Add to the ever growing list Avatar and Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows part two too as the former has only one drawn out conversation between Neytiri and her mother and guess what they talk about in it? Jake Sully! The latter one comes across as a shock. There are instances like Molly Weasley calling Bellatrix Lestrange a rather wonderful word but talking in one or two sentences without a reply from the other side is not exactly a conversation (Something people who are having relationship issues should keep in mind.) &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the list of movies which do not satisfy these conditions grows there are indeed a few movies which pass this test, Toy Story 3 being one of them (#FaithInHumanityRestored?). If you can’t remember two women conversing in that absolute gold of a movie, here’s a reason to go watch it again! Bechdel Test is obviously not an ironclad measure of well-rounded gender portrayal but one must agree it is an effective tool to indicate the huge sexism. As directors become more and more aware of this fact, we expect movies to take a turn for the good but till then whenever you see a typical one dimensional female character in a male driven comedy who lacks apparent depth make sure to condemn the discriminatory representation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 21:20:35 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>https://rishabhc.github.io/gg/2015/04/01/the-bechdel-test/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://rishabhc.github.io/gg/2015/04/01/the-bechdel-test/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Puns and Wordplay</title>
        <description>&lt;h6 id=&quot;i-wrote-this-as-an-article-for-geek-gazette&amp;#39;s-spring-2015-edition.&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;I wrote this as an article for &lt;a href=&quot;http://gg.ieeeiitr.com/&quot;&gt;Geek Gazette&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; Spring 2015 edition.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You drive past a Subway and notice a billboard in front which spells out “&lt;em&gt;Lettuce Meat Olive your Eggspectations&lt;/em&gt;” and at that moment you appreciate each and every miniscule change that took place in our language from the beginning of time to make this pun possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;English as we know it now has undergone rapid transformations and is obviously completely different from what it used to be even a few hundred years ago. Talking about the history of the language we must ponder upon the contributions of William Shakespeare as his works define what English is today. Many of us revere him but most of us are unaware of the fact that what Shakespeare wrote was considered absurd and nonsensical in his time. Shakespeare coined various new words and used the slang of his age thus driving home a judgement of “vulgar and hostile” on his works by the reading enthusiasts of the 16th century . Who is to say whether the ‘ghetto’ language of today is in the mainstream a few decades from now?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The evolution of our languages in the right direction may be the very reason that puns exist. For example the moment after completing a very arduous math problem could be (and should be) called an aftermath in the true sense of the word. Also we can’t definitely say that if it had evolved in a different direction wordplay wouldn’t be possible, instead the human tendency to joke around would have ensured that that wouldn’t happen. This particular tendency has widened the range of each and every language on the face of Earth. Taking English for an instance, the word ‘boo’ has given rise to an interesting connection between two festivities, namely Valentine’s day and Halloween as the word makes sense on both the days but for a loved one on 14th february and the sound made by a ghost on the last day of october. Just think of the humor this very simple connection can give birth to. And don’t even get me started on the word ‘bae’. Overused in each and every conversation now a days, the word has been a pivotal point or the punchline of hilarity in today’s era like the one we just read on Tumblr a few days ago; What do you call a loved one that controls you? Guantanamo Bae.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To conclude here is another pun, “&lt;strong&gt;Any salad is a caesar salad if you stab it hard enough&lt;/strong&gt;”. We must take a moment and thank William Shakespeare and the guy who thought ‘caesar’ would be a good name for a salad. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2015 17:47:07 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>https://rishabhc.github.io/gg/2015/03/31/puns-and-wordplay/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://rishabhc.github.io/gg/2015/03/31/puns-and-wordplay/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
